Guide to the African Americans in Film Collection, 1919-2000 RL.00019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
African Americans in Film Collection
1919-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00019
15 Linear Feet
The African Americans in Film collection includes ephemeral materials, especially posters and pressbooks, promoting and advertising motion pictures featuring Black actors, directors, and production companies.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The African Americans in Film Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase from George Robert Minkoff Inc. in 2001, 2009, 2010, and 2014, and Michael Bowen in 2020, 2022, and 2023.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by film title.
Biographical / Historical
Motion picture films have been created in the United States, primarily in southern California, since the very early 20th century.
The Norman Film Manufacturing Company was created in the late 1910s by Richard Norman and produced films with all-Black casts, known at the time as "race films". Race films were those movies made specifically for African American audiences and with African American casts. The studio produced silent films including The Green-Eyed Monster (1919), The Love Bug (1919), The Bull Dogger (1921), Crimson Skull (1921), Regeneration (1923), The Flying Ace (1926), and Black Gold (1928). The company and studio was located in Jacksonville, FL, along with a number of other studios in the 1910s and 1920s, but when the film industry adopted talking films and shifted to Hollywood, CA, the Norman Film Manufacturing Company moved to distributing films, then exhibiting films, before shutting down in the 1940s. The only surviving film is the Flying Ace, which was restored by the Library of Congress and is available for viewing online.
Pressbooks were marketing and promotional tools created by film distributors and sent to movie theaters. Pressbooks usually included images of posters, lobby cards, and other advertising materials available to promote the film, as well as suggestions or guides for advertising and promotion. Pressbooks came in a wide variety of sizes and could also include additional information about the film and cast itself. Pressbooks were commonly produced by major film studios from the 1910s onward.
Collection Overview
The African Americans in Film collection includes ephemeral materials promoting and advertising motion pictures featuring Black actors, directors, and production companies. Materials in this collection include press books, posters, promotional booklets, campaign books, advertising manuals, programs, lobby cards, and other formats. The films documented include silent films, Blaxploitation films, blockbuster action films, musicals, documentaries, and dramas, from smaller Black owned and operated companies to major studio productions. Actors frequently featured in films documented here include Sidney Poitier, Dorothy Dandridge, Pam Grier, Jim Brown, Brock Peters, Fred Williamson, Ruby Dee, Brenda Sykes, Sammie Davis Jr., James Earl Jones, and many others.
Description often includes the format of the material and/or one or more of the Black stars featured in the film. Some description provided by George Robert Minkoff Inc., the dealer from whom part of the collection was purchased, is provided in quotes. Some of that description may have originated from the books Blacks in American films and television: an encyclopedia. and Toms, coons, mulattoes, mammies, and bucks: an interpretive history of Blacks in American films., both by Donald Bogle. The majority of the materials are from the United States, but a few items were created by or for audiences in other countries such as Japan, Denmark, France, Germany, and the United Kingdom, and are noted as such.
African Americans in the motion picture industry; African American motion picture producers and directors; Motion pictures -- Marketing; African American motion picture actors and actresses; African American women in motion pictures; Advertising -- Motion pictures; Ephemera; African Americans in motion pictures; Motion picture industry -- United States; Motion pictures -- United States; Motion pictures -- Distribution; Blaxploitation films; Race relations in motion pictures; Norman Film Manufacturing Company; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
- 48 Hours, 1982 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  French press book; Starring Eddie Murphy.
- A.K.A. Cassius Clay, 1970 (Box 1)
  "Feature about the legendary boxer Muhammad Ali."
- Aaron Loves Angela, 1975 (Oversize-folder 14)
  poster; white snipe over rating bug
- Abby, 1974 (Oversize-folder 1)
  poster
- Across 110th Street, 1972 (Box 5)
  pressbook
- Action Jackson, 1988 (Oversize-folder 14)
- Adios Amigo, 1975 (Oversize-folder 14)
- Airport '77, 1977 (Box 1)
  British advertising promotion guide sheet
- Airport '77, 1977 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Robert Hooks.
- All the Young Men, 1960 (Box 1)
  Advertising supplement; "Publicity specifically designed for Black audiences."
- Amazing Grace, 1974 (Oversize-folder 14)
- Amazing Grace, 1974 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Moms Mabley and Stepin Fetchit.
- American Gigolo, 1980 (Box 1)
  Starring Bill Duke.
- American Gigolo, 1980 (Box 1)
  British press kit
- Amistad, 1997 (Box 1)
  Japanese promotional booklet; Starring Djimon Hounsou.
- Angel Levine, The, 1970 (Box 1)
  "Harry Belafonte produced and starred in this adaptation of Bernard Malamud."
- Angela Davis l'enchainement, 1977 (Tube 1)
- Angels in the Outfield, 1994 (Box 1)
  Promotional booklet; "Sent out by Disney and containing an article about Danny Glover and the film."
- Anna Lucasta, 1959 (Box 5)
- Anna's Sin, 1961 (Oversize-folder 14)
- Another 48 Hrs, 1990 (Box 1)
  Japanese promotional brochure; Starring Eddie Murphy.
- Baby Needs a New Pair of Shoes, 1974 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Bad Bunch, The, 1973 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Bamboo Gods and Iron Men, 1974 (Box 5)
- Bamboo Gods and Iron Men, 1974 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Bamboozled, 2000 (Box 1)
  "Spike Lee directed this film about a frustrated African American TV writer who proposes a blackface minstrel show in protest, but it becomes a hit, to his chagrin. Starring Damon Wayans, Savion Glover, Jada Pinkett Smith and Tommy Davidson."
- Beverly Hills Cop II, 1987 (Oversize-folder 15)
- Big Doll House, The, 1971 (Box 1)
  "Pam Grier in one of her early starring roles."
- Big Score, The, 1983 (Oversize-folder 15)
- Billy Jack, 1971 (Box 1)
- Billy Jack, 1971 (Box 1)
- Bingo Long Traveling All-Stars, 1976 (Oversize-folder 15)
- Bird, 1988 (Box 1)
  French press sheet; "Clint Eastwood directed this biography of the legendary Charlie Parker, who was portrayed by Forest Whitaker."
- Biscuit Eater, 1972 (Oversize-folder 15)
- Black Belt Jones, 1974 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Jim Kelly and Scatman Crothers.
- Black Belt Jones, 1974 (Box 1)
  Promotional booklet done like a comic book
- Black Caesar, 1973 (Box 1)
  Starring Fred Williamson.
- Black Dragon vs. the Yellow Tiger, 1974 (Oversize-folder 15)
- Black Dragon's Revenge, 1975 (Oversize-folder 15)
  poster; moderate handling
- Black Eye, 1974 (Box 5)
- Black Fist, 1975 (Oversize-folder 16)
- Black Gestapo, 1973 (Box 5)
  lithograph print
- Black Girl, 1972 (Box 1)
  Press book; Ossie Davis (director). Starring Leslie Uggams and Ruby Dee.
- Black Girl, 1972 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Black Gold, 1927 (Box 1)
  "Black-cast drama about oil-drilling from the Norman Film Manufacturing Company."
- Black Heat, 1976 (Box 5)
- Black Jack, 1973 (Oversize-folder 16)
- Black Mama, White Mama, 1972 (Box 1)
  Starring Pam Grier.
- Black Moses of Soul, 1973 (Oversize-folder 2)
- Black Rodeo, 1972 (Box 1)
  Press book; "Rodeo documentary, with guest appearances by Muhammad Ali and Woody Strode."
- Black Samson, 1974 (Box 5)
- Black Samson, 1974 (Oversize-folder 2)
- Black Samurai, 1976 (Box 5)
- Black Samurai, 1977 (Oversize-folder 16)
- Black Shampoo, 1976 (Box 5)
- Black Shampoo, 1976 (Box 1)
  "Blaxploitation film starring John Daniels and Tanya Boyd."
- Black Street Fighter, 1975 (Oversize-folder 16)
  poster; modest seam wear
- Blacula, 1972 (Box 5)
  lobby card
- Blacula, 1972 (Oversize-folder 16)
- Blast, 1976 (Oversize-folder 17)
- Blazing Stewardesses, 1974 (Box 1)
- Body and Soul, 1981 (Oversize-folder 17)
  poster; A style; small patch repair
- Body and Soul, 1981 (Oversize-folder 17)
  poster; B style; crunched corner
- Book of Numbers, 1973 (Box 1)
  Starring Raymond St. Jacques.
- Book of Numbers, 1973 (Oversize-folder 2)
- Bright Road, 1953 (Box 5)
  pressbook, lobby card
- Bright Road, 1953 (Box 5)
  press photographs
- Bronco Billy, 1980 (Box 1)
  Special promotional booklet; "Synopses in English, Spanish, French, German and Italian."
- Bronze Venus, 1943 (Box 1)
  "Reissue of 1938 film The Duke is Tops; Lena Horne's debut film and a very rare specimen of Black independent filmmaking."
- Brother John, 1971 (Box 5)
- Brother John, 1971 (Oversize-folder 17)
- Brother Martin, Servant of Jesus, 1942 (Oversize-folder 17)
  poster; All-black cast
- Brothers, 1977 (Oversize-folder 18)
- Brubaker, 1980 (Box 1)
  British press book
- Brubaker, 1980 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Yaphet Kotto.
- Buck and the Preacher, 1972 (Box 5)
- Buck and the Preacher, 1972 (Oversize-folder 2)
- Bucktown, 1975 (Oversize-folder 2)
- Bull-Dogger, The, 1921 (Box 1)
  "Advertising flyer for four Norman Film Manufacturing Company Black-cast films suggested as a quadruple bill: The Love Bug ( 1919), The Crimson Skull ( 1921), The Green-Eyed Monster ( 1919) and The Bull-Dogger ( 1921)."
- Burn!, 1970 (Box 1)
  "Film directed by Gillo Pontecorvo about a slave revolt on a Caribbean island early in the 19th century."
- Bus is Coming, The, 1971 (Box 1)
  Starring Mike Sims.
- Bus is Coming, The, 1971 (Oversize-folder 3)
- Candy Tangerine Man, 1975 (Oversize-folder 18)
- Can't Stop the Music, 1980 (Box 1)
  Campaign press book; Starring Alex Briley and Ray Simpson.
- Car Wash, 1976 (Box 6)
- Carbon Copy, 1981 (Box 5)
- Carbon Copy, 1981 (Oversize-folder 18)
- Cardinal, The, 1963 (Box 1)
  "Ossie Davis portrays a Southern Roman Catholic priest whose church has been burned by the KKK."
- Carmen Jones, 1954 (Box 1)
  Danish theater program; "Program is extensively illustrated."
- Carmen Jones, 1954 (Box 5)
  Lobby cards (2): "Poster is in color and shows actor Harry Belafonte, standing, kissing the feet of actress Dorothy Dandridge, who is sitting on the edge of a table. Visible graphic dimensions: 10.75x13.75 inches."
- Celebration at Big Sur, 1971 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Dorothy Morrison and the Combs Sisters.
- Chain Gang Women, 1971 (Box 1)
- Change of Mind, 1969 (Box 5)
  premiere program
- Change of Mind, 1969 (Box 1)
  Ad supplement
- Change of Mind, 1969 (Box 1)
  Starring Raymond St. Jacques. "The brain of a white district attorney is transplanted into the body of a Black man."
- Change of Mind, 1969 (Oversize-folder 3)
- Charley One-Eye, 1973 (Oversize-folder 18)
- Charley-One-Eye, 1972 (Box 1)
  Press book; "Richard Roundtree in a Blaxploitation western."
- Chase for the Golden Needles, 1974 (Box 1)
  Campaign manual; Starring Jim Kelly.
- Checkerboard, 1959 (Box 1)
  Exhibitor's manual; "American release of the French film Les Tripes Au Soleil, a film whose setting is unclear (it seems to be a French film set in the Old West), with the cast equally divided between Black and white actors."
- Clara's Heart, 1988 (Oversize-folder 18)
  poster; extra fold
- Claudine, 1974 (Tube 1)
- Claudine, 1974 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring James Earl Jones and Diahann Carroll.
- Claudine, 1974 (Oversize-folder 3)
- Clay Pigeon, 1971 (Box 1)
  Exhibitor's campaign book; Starring Ivan Dixon.
- Cleopatra Jones, 1973 (Oversize-folder 19)
  poster; B style
- Cleopatra Jones and the Casino of Gold, 1975 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Tamara Dobson.
- Cleopatra Jones, 1973 (Box 1)
- Cleopatra Jones, 1973 (Box 5)
  premier program
- Coffy, 1973 (Box 1)
- Color Purple, 1985 (Box 5)
- Color Purple, The, 1985 (Oversize-folder 19)
  poster; A style
- Color Purple, The, 1985 (Oversize-folder 19)
- Color Purple, 1985 (Box 1)
  Exhibitor's campaign book (British press book)
- Come Back Charleston Blue, 1972 (Oversize-folder 19)
  poster; white snipe over rating
- Come Back, Charleston Blue, 1972 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Godfrey Cambridge and Raymond St. Jacques. "This is a sequel to Cotton Comes to Harlem, adapted, like its precursor, from Chester Himes."
- Come on, Cowboy, 1948 (Oversize-folder 19)
- Condor, El, 1970 (Box 1)
  Starring Jim Brown.
- Cool Breeze, 1972 (Box 1)
  Press book; Starring Pam Grier and Thalmus Rasulala.
- Cool Breeze, 1972 (Oversize-folder 3)
- The Cool World, circa 1963 (Box 6)
  Pressbook; directed by Shirley Clarke.
- Cooley High, 1975 (Oversize-folder 20)
- Coonskin, 1974 (Box 5)
- Coonskin, 1975 (Oversize-folder 20)
- Cornbread, Earl and Me, 1975 (Box 5)
- Cotton Club, 1984 (Box 1)
  Japanese promotional brochure; Starring Gregory Hines.
- Cotton Comes to Harlem, 1970 (Box 5)
- Countdown at Kusini, 1976 (Box 5)
- Countdown at Kusini, 1976 (Oversize-folder 3)
- Countdown at Kusini, 1976 (Oversize-folder 20)
  poster; credit correction; snipe glue to bottom
- Crimson Skull, 1921 (Box 1)
  "From the Norman Film Manufacturing Company: Baffling Western Mystery Photo-Play. Supported by Bill Pickett, World's Champion Wild West Performer, the one-legged Marvel, Steve Reynolds, and 30 Colored Cowboys. Produced in the All-Colored City of Boley, Okla. An Epic of Wild Life and Smoking Revolvers. All-Colored Cast. Contains an article by star Anita Bush, Introduction of Negro Drama in New York."
- Crimson Skull, 1921 (Box 1)
- Dark of the Sun, 1968 (Box 2)
- Death Journey, 1976 (Oversize-folder 4)
- Decks Ran Red, The, 1958 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Dorothy Dandridge.
- Defiant Ones, The, 1958 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Sidney Poitier.
- Deliver Us from Evil, 1975 (Oversize-folder 20)
- Demolition Man, 1993 (Box 2)
  Japanese promotional booklet; Starring Wesley Snipes.
- Detective, The, 1968 (Box 2)
  Starring Al Freeman, Jr.
- Detective, The, 1968 (Box 2)
- Detroit 9000, 1973 (Box 5)
- Detroit 9000, 1973 (Oversize-folder 20)
- Devil and Max Devlin, The, 1981 (Box 2)
  Ad pad
- Diamonds, 1975 (Box 2)
- Die Hard with a Vengeance, 1995 (Box 2)
  Japanese promotional booklet; Starring Samuel L. Jackson.
- Disco Godfather, 1979 (Oversize-folder 21)
- Do the Right Thing, 1989 (Oversize-folder 21)
- Double Possession (a.k.a. Ganja & Hess), 1973 (Box 5)
- Dr. Black Mr. Hyde, 1976 (Oversize-folder 21)
- Drum, 1976 (Box 2)
- Duel at Diablo, 1966 (Box 2)
- Duel at Diablo, 1966 (Box 2)
  Advertising supplement
- Earthquake, 1974 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Richard Roundtree.
- Ebony Ivory & Jade, 1976 (Box 2)
  "Action film with female stars, one African-American, one Caucasian, and one Asian."
- Edge of the City, 1957 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Sidney Poitier and Ruby Dee.
- Education of Sonny Carson, 1974 (Box 5)
- Education of Sonny Carson, 1974 (Oversize-folder 4)
- Emma Mae, 1976 (Oversize-folder 4)
- Evil in the Deep, 1976 (Box 2)
  Starring Rosey Greer.
- Fatal Beauty, 1987 (Oversize-folder 21)
- Fight Never Ends, The, 1948 (Box 5)
- Fighting Mad, 1978 (Oversize-folder 21)
- Final Comedown, The, 1972 (Box 2)
  Starring Billy Dee Williams.
- Five on the Black Hand Side, 1973 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Ja'net DuBois, Virginia Capers, and Sonny Jim Gaines.
- Five on the Black Hand Side, 1973 (Oversize-folder 4)
- Flying Ace, The, 1926 (Box 2)
  "A Black-cast aviation drama from the Norman Film Manufacturing Company."
- For Love of Ivy, 1968 (Box 2)
  Press book; "Sidney Poitier starred in this film; screenplay from an original story by Poitier."
- Force Four, 1975 (Oversize-folder 22)
  poster; wear at folds
- Fort Apache, The Bronx, 1981 (Box 2)
  British press book; Starring Pam Grier.
- Foxtrap, 1986 (Oversize-folder 22)
- Foxy Brown, 1974 (Box 2)
- Foxy Brown, 1974 (Box 5)
  sell sheets
- Friday Foster, 1976 (Box 5)
- Friday Foster, 1976 (Oversize-folder 22)
  poster; NSS stamp on bottom border
- From Nashville with Music, 1969 (Box 2)
  "Country and western musical film, racially integrated by the presence of singer Charley Pride."
- Georgia Georgia, 1972 (Oversize-folder 4)
- Georgia, Georgia, 1972 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Diane Sands. Script by Maya Angelou.
- Get Rollin', 1980 (Oversize-folder 22)
- Ghostbusters II, 1989 (Box 2)
  British press book; Starring Ernie Hudson.
- Glory, 1989 (Box 2)
  Promotional book; Starring Denzel Washington, Morgan Freeman, and Andre Braugher. "Sumptuously illustrated book on the film, printed in a small edition for circulation to major theater chains."
- Glory, 1989 (Box 2)
  Broadsides; "Four broadsides used in the movie. Includes: "Proclamation... April 10, 1863" (2 copies); "The Enemy is Approaching;" and "Regulations for Camp Readville.""
- God's Step Children, 1938 (Box 5)
  Lobby card; "Directed by Oscar Micheaux. From the story Naomi, Negress. Poster, circa 1938, is in color and shows a seated man on left, bending over a distressed woman lying sick in bed. Visible graphic dimensions: 10.75x13.75 inches."
- Going to Glory... Come to Jesus, 1946 (Box 2)
  Lobby cards and bag; "Eight lobby cards used to advertise the movie in theater lobbies, along with the paper bag for the cards."
- Gone Are the Days, 1963 (Box 5)
- Gone with the Wind [The Story of], 1939 (Box 2)
  Reissued 1967; Starring Hattie McDaniel.
- Gone with the Wind, 1939 (Box 2)
- Gordon's War, 1973 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Paul Winfield. Bogle, p. 96: [Winfield] portrays a Vietnam veteran returning home to New York to a dead wife, the victim of a drug overdose. Enlisting the aid of three other Viet vets, he becomes a vigilante, determined to rub out the dope dealers.
- Gordon's War, 1973 (Box 2)
  Promotional brochure
- Gordon's War, 1973 (Oversize-folder 5)
- Grand Canyon, 1991 (Box 2)
  British press book; Starring Danny Glover.
- Grasshopper, The, 1970 (Box 2)
- Grasshopper, The, 1970 (Box 2)
- Great White Hope, The, 1970 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring James Earl Jones.
- Great White Hope, The, 1970 (Oversize-folder 5)
- Greatest, The, 1977 (Box 5)
- Green-Eyed Monster, The, 1919 (Box 2)
- Guess Who's Coming to Dinner, 1967 (Box 5)
- Guess Who's Coming to Dinner?, 1967 (Oversize-folder 22)
  poster; patch repair, stains in border
- Guess Who's Coming to Dinner, 1969 (Box 2)
  1969 reissue of 1967 film on double-bill with 1966 film To Sir, With Love; Starring Sidney Poitier.
- Guy from Harlem, The, 1977 (Oversize-folder 23)
- Halls of Anger, 1970 (Box 2)
  Starring Calvin Lockhart.
- Halls of Anger, 1970 (Oversize-folder 5)
- Hammer, 1972 (Box 2)
- Hangup, 1974 (Oversize-folder 5)
- Heart is a Lonely Hunter, The, 1968 (Box 2)
  Pressbook; "Cicely Tyson in a Carson McCullers adaptation."
- Heart is a Lonely Hunter, The, 1968 (Box 2)
  Special promotional flyer
- Hero Ain't Nothin' But a Sandwich, A, 1978 (Oversize-folder 5)
- Hickey & Boggs, 1972 (Box 2)
  "Detective film, starred Bill Cosby with his costar from the I Spy television series of the 1960s, Robert Culp."
- Hit Man, 1973 (Oversize-folder 23)
- Hit Man, 1972 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Bernie Casey.
- Hit!, 1973 (Box 2)
  Press book and merchandising manual; Starring Billie Dee Williams and Richard Pryor.
- Home of the Brave, 1949 (Box 5)
- Honky, 1971 (Box 5)
- Honky, 1971 (Box 2)
  Starring Brenda Sykes.
- Hurricane Smith, 1992 (Oversize-folder 23)
- Hurry Sundown, 1967 (Oversize-folder 23)
- Hurry Sundown, 1967 (Box 2)
  Press book ad supplement
- I Crossed the Color Line, 1966 (Box 2)
  Starring Max Julien.
- I Escaped from Devil's Island, 1973 (Oversize-folder 23)
- I Escaped From Devil's Island, 1973 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Jim Brown.
- I Escaped from Devil's Island, 1973 (Oversize-folder 6)
- I'm Gonna Get You, Sucka, 1988 (Oversize-folder 24)
- If He Hollers Let Him Go, 1968 (Oversize-folder 24)
- If He Hollers Let Him Go!, 1968 (Box 5)
- In the Heat of the Night, 1967 (Box 2)
  Danish illustrated theater program
- In the Heat of the Night, 1967 (Box 2)
  Special ad supplement; "Issued in conjunction with the film's winning two Oscars."
- Incident, The, 1967 (Box 2)
  Press book; Starring Ruby Dee and Brock Peters.
- Introducing Dorothy Dandridge, 1999 (Box 2)
  Starring Halle Berry.
- J. D.'s Revenge, 1976 (Box 5)
- J. D.'s Revenge, 1976 (Oversize-folder 6)
- Jimmy the Kid, 1982 (Oversize-folder 24)
- Jive Turkey, 1974; 1976 (Box 5)
- Jumpin' Jack Flash, 1986 (Oversize-folder 24)
- Kenner, 1968 (Tube 1)
- Kenner, 1969 (Box 2)
- Kill Squad, 1981 (Box 2)
- Klansman, The, 1974 (Box 2)
  Advertising booklet
- Klansman, The, 1974 (Box 2)
  Supplementary advertising sheets
- Klansman, The, 1974 (Oversize-folder 24)
  poster; A style; moderate wear
- Krush Groove, 1985 (Oversize-folder 25)
- Lady Cocoa, 1975 (Oversize-folder 6)
- Lady Sings the Blues, 1972 (Box 3)
  Starring Diana Ross, Billy Dee Williams, and Richard Pryor.
- Lady Sings the Blues, 1972 (Box 3)
  Advertising
- Lady Sings the Blues, 1972 (Box 3)
- Landlord, The, 1970 (Box 3)
  Screenplay by William Gunn. Starring Pearl Bailey, Diana Sands, and Louis Gossett Jr.
- Last Dragon, The, 1985 (Oversize-folder 25)
- Last of the Mobile Hot-Shots, 1969 (Box 3)
  Press book; "Robert Hooks in a Tennesse Williams adaptation of The Seven Descents of Myrtle."
- Leadbelly, 1976 (Oversize-folder 6)
- Leaning Tree, The, 1970 (Oversize-folder 6)
- Learning Tree, 1969 (Tube 1)
- Learning Tree, The, 1969 (Box 3)
  Press book; Director and producer: Gordon Parks.
- Learning Tree, The, 1969 (Box 3)
  Promotional flyer
- Legend of N*gger Charley, 1972 (Oversize-folder 25)
- Legend of Nigger Charley, 1972 (Box 5)
- Let No Man Write My Epitaph, 1960 (Box 3)
  "Ella Fitzgerald's first dramatic role, that of a nightclub singer in a Skid Row bar."
- Let's Do It Again, 1975 (Oversize-folder 25)
- Lialeh, 1974 (Oversize-folder 25)
- Liberation of L. B. Jones, 1970 (Oversize-folder 26)
- Liberation of L.B. Jones, The, 1970 (Box 3)
  Press book insert
- Liberation of L.B. Jones, The, 1970 (Box 3)
  Press book insert; "This press book insert was especially prepared for placement in Negro newspapers."
- Liberation of L.B. Jones, The, 1970 (Box 3)
- Lifeboat, 1944 (Box 3)
  Danish souvenir program; "All original materials from Lifeboat are extremely uncommon. Canada Lee co-starred in this Hitchcock film from a script by John Steinbeck. Lee's performance is often cited by historians as an early case of a Black actor playing a non-stereotypical role in a major Hollywood film."
- Lilies of the Field, 1963 (Oversize-folder 26)
- Lilies of the Field, 1963 (Box 3)
- Lilies of the Field, 1963 (Box 3)
- Long Night, The, 1976 (Oversize-folder 7)
- Long Ships, The, 1963 (Box 3)
  Starring Sidney Poitier.
- Lord Shango, 1975 (Oversize-folder 7)
- Lost in the Stars, 1974 (Oversize-folder 7)
- Lost Man, The, 1969 (Box 3)
- Lost Man, The, 1969 (Box 3)
- Love Bug, The, 1919 (Box 3)
  Advertising flyer; "Advertising flyer for four Norman Film Manufacturing Company Black-cast films suggested as a quadruple bill: The Love Bug ( 1919), The Crimson Skull ( 1921), The Green-Eyed Monster ( 1919) and The Bull-Dogger ( 1921)."
- L-Shaped Room, The, 1962 (Box 3)
- L-Shaped Room, The, 1962 (Box 3)
  Press book; Starring Brock Peters.
- L-Shaped Room, The, 1962 (Box 3)
- Mack, The, 1977 (Box 3)
  1977 reissue of 1973 film; Starring Richard Pryor.
- Mahogany, 1975 (Oversize-folder 7)
- Malaga, 1962 (Box 3)
  Press book; Starring Dorothy Dandridge,
- Malcolm X, 1972 (Oversize-folder 26)
- Malcolm X, 1972 (Box 3)